redenergy.com.au 2013-05-21

# Privacy Policy | Red Energy

This website is operated by Red Energy Pty Ltd ABN 60 107 479 372 ( **Red Energy** ) under the domain name www.redenergy.com.au.

We understand that your privacy is important to you. Red Energy is committed to compliance with the laws that protect your personal information, including the Privacy Act 1988 and the National Privacy Principles. The Red Energy Website Privacy Policy explains how your personal information (being information capable of identifying you as an individual) is treated as you access and interact with this website. The practices outlined in this policy are subject to any rights or obligations we may have to handle personal information in accordance with law. This policy only applies if you are using this website as an individual, and not if you are using it on behalf of a company. 

Obviously you will need to give us some personal information so that we can supply energy to you (if you are a customer) and to provide some of the features available on this website. It is important that this personal information and any other information you give us is correct and that you tell us if there is any change to it. 

By registering for Red Energy’s online services, you confirm that you are the account holder or are authorised by the account holder to access the accounts for which you have registered, or for any accounts that you add to your online profile in the future. 

Where there is a registration facility on our website, we will ask you whether you want us to send you personalised emails, mail and other communications with news, special offers and other matters which may be of interest to you. You can say no to this service either when you register or by contacting us.

We will maintain the security of your personal information in accordance with our Security Policy. However, we may share your personal information with:

  * any network operator that we work with to supply energy to you, if they request it;
  * our related companies;
  * any of our service providers including organisations that assist us with billing, meter reading, connections and repairs, technology and security services; and
  * our professional advisers including lawyers, marketing and business advisers and auditors.

Where this involves transferring your personal information to another country, we observe applicable privacy law and principles. Otherwise we will only release your personal information and collect other information about you if you authorise us to do this, if we are legally required or authorised to, or to enable us to:

  * carry out credit checks or otherwise assess your creditworthiness; or 
  * carry out our responsibilities, or exercise our rights under our energy supply agreement with you; or 
  * advise you of any products or services which we consider may be of interest to you; or
  * conduct, or contact you for the purpose of market research; or 
  * collect debts; or 
  * implement any scheme for the payment of rebates or granting of concessions to customers; or
  * provide you with any services you have requested. 

If you want to request access to personal information we hold about you, just contact us. Please provide as much detail as you can about the particular information you seek in order to help us retrieve it. In accordance with the Privacy Act, a fee may be charged to cover our costs of providing access to you. You may ask for any of your personal information to be corrected, so that it is accurate, complete and up to date. We will consider any such request in good faith and inform you of the action taken.

We may conduct customer surveys on the website to collect statistics for marketing and research purposes. You can choose not to participate in these surveys.

The Red Energy website may contain links to other sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites. You should check those sites for their privacy statements. 

### Cookies

Red Energy uses 'cookies' to provide a secure, personalised experience on the website. Cookies are small data files that a website is able to place on a user’s computer hard drive or in its memory to record aspects of that user’s experience of the website. On this website cookies will never contain or store any information about a user - they will simply be used as an identifier. You'll need to have cookies 'enabled' in your browser to access the signed in areas of our site. 

This website uses cookies in two different ways:

  * When you are browsing any part of our site we will use a cookie that is stored on a computer's hard drive to track where visitors go on the site. The cookie does not allow us to identify any individual.
  * When you register and sign in to the secure, personalised area of the website we'll send you a secure cookie that will only last for the duration of your session. This secure cookie will be stored in your computer's memory rather than on your hard drive, and it maintains the security of your session.

This website also uses clear gifs for technical spacing purposes on the website. We do not use clear gifs or web beacons for tracking your activity on the website.   
Variations to this Privacy Policy

Red Energy may from time to time update this policy. We encourage you to check this policy regularly. 

Version 2 - August 3rd 2004
